DOMINIC JOHN BENNETT

Details: dominic.john.bennett@gmail.com // + 46 76 88 38 66 4 // Irish/British

Web: dominicjbennett.com // GitHub // Google Scholar

Address: Nils Dahlbecks gata 5, lgh. 1401, Göteborg, 412 49 Sweden

Adept researcher, data analyst and software developer with demonstrated history in academia.

6+ years of experience in statistics, data analysis, (bio-)informatics as well as technical writing, languages and public speaking.

Experience

2017 - Present Postdoctoral researcher | Open-source developer

Developing a modular pipeline for automated phylogeny generation in R, University of Gothenburg

& Gothenburg Global Biodiversity Centre, Sweden.

2018 - Present Open-source code reviewer

R package reviewer for ROpenSci, https://ropensci.org/

2015 - 2017 Online resources coordinator

Quantitative Ecology Special Interest Group, British Ecological Society.

2012 Text-mining research intern

Nucleotide sequence discovery in scientific and legal texts. Linguamatics, Cambridge, U.K.

2010 - 2011 Researcher in population genetics

Population genetics of fungus, Microbotryum. Université Paris-Sud, Paris, France.

2009 Conservation volunteer

Field experience in rainforest with Operation Wallacea. Buton Island, Sulawesi, Indonesia.

Education

2013 - 2017 **PhD** in Evolutionary Biology and Palaeobiology

Imperial College London & Zoological Society of London, U.K.

2012 - 2013 MRes in Genomics and Biodiversity Informatics, Distinction

Imperial College London, U.K.

2008 - 2012 **BSc** in Biology with French for Science, First Class Honours

Imperial College London, U.K. & Université Paris-Sud, France

Skills

Computer

Primary R and python

Secondary C, Java, SQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Perl, MatLab and Ruby

Other LINUX, UNIX, HPC facility, docker, Git, Travis-CI, Coveralls, Jekyll, Hugo

<u>Human</u>

Academic articles 6 first-authorships, 8 co-authorships

Communication Technical writing, creative writing, proofreading, teaching, presenting and public

speaking

Languages French (C2), Swedish (B1), Spanish (A2) and Japanese (A2)

Selected Software

outsider	Install and run programs, outside of R, inside of R	<u>GitHub</u>	R
restez	Create and query a local copy of GenBank in R	CRAN, ROpenSci	R
phylotaR	An automated pipeline for retrieving orthologous DNA sequences from GenBank	CRAN, ROpenSci	R
treeman	Intuitive manipulation of phylogenetic trees in R	CRAN, GitHub	R, C
TNR	Resolution of taxonomic names in python	<u>PyPi</u> , <u>GitHub</u>	python
pG-lt	An automated pipeline for converting taxonomic names into phylogenetic trees	<u>PyPi, GitHub</u>	python

Selected Publications

Evolutionarily distinct "living fossils" require both lower speciation and lower extinction rates	Bennett, D.J., Sutton, M.D. & Turvey, S.T.	Paleobiology
Quantifying the living fossil concept	Bennett, D.J., Sutton, M.D. & Turvey, S.T.	Palaeontologia Electronica
How the Past Impacts the Future: Modelling the Performance of Evolutionarily Distinct Mammals through Time.	Bennett, D.J., Sutton, M.D. & Turvey, S.T.	Phil. Trans. B. (In press)
phylotaR: An automated pipeline for retrieving orthologous DNA sequences from GenBank in R	Bennett, D.J., Hettling, H., Silvestro, D. et al.	<u>Life</u>
restez: Create and Query a Local Copy of GenBank in R.	Bennett, D.J., Hettling, H., Silvestro, D. et al.	<u>JOSS</u>
treeman: an R package for efficient and intuitive manipulation of phylogenetic trees	Bennett, D.J., Sutton, M.D. & Turvey, S.T.	BMC research notes

References

Alexandre Antonelli Mark D. Sutton Samuel T. Turvey

Director of Science, Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew Senior Lecturer in Palaeontology, Institute of Zoology, London

<u>a.antonelli@kew.org</u> <u>m.sutton@imperial.ac.uk</u> <u>samuel.turvey@ioz.ac.uk</u>